本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：feilixiaozi  CS漫画家小明  潇湘月影  香茗小焙  某茶
翻译：王大可  杳杳  校对：油炸电风扇   香茗小焙
时间轴：今    永远的永远
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第三集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你接了个意外事故的案子
You took a case on contingency
原告还都是穷人
where every plaintiff is dirt poor.
撤销
Dump it.
我叔叔基思也是受害者之一
One of the victims was my uncle Keith.
这些人需要你的帮助
Please, these people need your help.
他们需要你这样的人为他们争取
They need someone like you to fight for them,
而我做不到
and I can't do it.
那你觉得我们一起做如何
Then what do you say we do it together?
我想提议对当前的薪酬计算方法
I'd like to propose a change to
进行调整
the current compensation formula.
如果我们投票的话
How many partners do you have in your pocket
你能调动多少合伙人支持
if we put your proposal to a vote?
45%
I can get 45%.
我能帮你通过投票
I'm gonna get you the difference.
这是哈维最近三个案子的收益表
This is Harvey's last three income statements,
我发现它们被放在复印机里
and I found them sitting in the copy machine.
是你主动为我工作的
You came to work for me,
你该作出决定了
so now it's time for you to decide.
你到底要不要站在我这边
Are you with me or not?
我刚刚要求明天就我的提议进行投票
I just called for a vote tomorrow,
希望你有存钱的习惯
and I hope you've been saving your money,
因为你那钱多事少的工作马上就要没了
because your gravy train's about to leave the station.
你好
Oh, hello.
-我只是  -在工作
- I was just... - Working.
我看到了  但现在刚早晨七点半
I see that, but it's 7:30 in the morning.
你来这么早干什么
What are you doing here so early?
我想在混乱开始之前到公司
I like to get in before the chaos starts.
跟你说实话吧  我以为
Tell you the truth, I was under the impression
你还要很久才会来
that you wouldn't get in till much later.
我想提前开始我的一天
I wanted to get a jump on the day.
那你也许该动手解决这项工作
Then maybe you should get a jump on this.
我为什么要支付路易的干洗账单
Why am I paying Louis's laundry bill?
因为如果你支付了
Because if you pay it,
他就不会知道我们给他所有的衬衫上了三倍浆
he won't know that we triple-starched all of his shirts.
-我们  -是的  我们
- We? - Yes, we.
他盯着我们不放  我们也不放过他
He came after us. We're coming after him.
你觉得我不会支持你吗
Did you think I wouldn't have your back?
你想听真话吗
You want the truth?
我以为你看了我挣多少钱以后
I thought you'd be asking for a raise
想要加薪呢
after seeing how much I make.
我没看你挣多少钱
I didn't look at how much you make.
而且我认为
And as far as I'm concerned,
看到的人都应该被开除
anyone who did should be fired.
你很不错  格蕾琴
You're all right, Gretchen.
但暂时不要再
But for the time being,
捉弄路易了
don't play any more jokes on Louis.
我能问问为什么吗
Mind if I ask why?
因为我要捉弄人
Because I only play jokes on people
是为了表达好感
to express my affection for them,
可现在我对路易・利特一点好感都没有
and right now I have no affection for Louis Litt.
看来我来的正是时候
Looks like I got here just in time.
为什么
And why is that?
因为我想让你做一些
Because I'm going to ask you to do something
你不愿意做的事
you're not going to want to do,
但不同的是  这次你会照做
only this time you're going to do it.
我上次怎么做的
What didn't I do last time?
我让你去和路易道歉
I told you to apologize to Louis.
我去了  就在他和杰克・索罗夫握手联盟
And I did, right before he held hands with Jack Soloff
在全公司面前削减我的收入之前
and cut my earnings in front of the entire firm.
但如果你一开始对杰克
And if you hadn't have been such a dick to Jack
友善一点的话
in the first place,
路易就无人可找了
Louis would have had nowhere to go.
这与路易无关是吧
This isn't about Louis, is it?
无关
No, it isn't.
我想你和杰克和解
I want you to bury the hatchet with Jack.
你是说你想我去拍他马屁
You mean you want me to kiss his ass.
我是说我想你找个办法
I mean I want you to figure out a way
去跟一个影响力逐渐上升的合伙人和平相处
to make peace with a partner whose influence is on the rise.
那就是拍他马屁啊
That's kissing his ass.
如果你是这么认为的
Well, if that's how you want to look at it,
那就忍着吧  因为他是个威胁
then pucker up, because that man is a threat,
而且他与路易结盟了
and he's aligned with Louis,
我可没心情进行权力斗争
and I am in no mood for a power struggle.
我今早都没听见你出门
I didn't hear you leave today.
因为我早上五点就走了
That's because I left at 5:00 in the morning,
想要早点着手处理这个案子
trying to get an early start on this case.
关于这件事
About that...
我昨晚不想发表意见
I didn't want to say anything last night
因为你看起来太兴奋了
because you were so excited--
但我和你父亲共事让你很担忧
But you're worried about me working with your father.
是的
Yes.
迈克  你们是我人生中最重要的两个男人
Mike, you're the two most important men in my life.
但你俩都是不愿退让的性格
Neither of you back down from a fight,
我只是
and I'm just--
我怕你们最终会憎恨对方
I'm afraid you're gonna end up hating each other.
瑞秋  你恨你的父亲吗
Rachel, do you hate your father?
当然不了  我爱我爸爸
Of course not. I love my dad.
那你不是也时时和他有冲突吗
And don't you have conflicts with him all the time?
是的  但这不一样
Yes, I do, but it's different.
他是我的家人
He's my family.
是啊  他也要成为我的家人了
Yeah, he's gonna be my family too.
如果我足够幸运的话  将会在以后的许多年
And if I'm lucky, I'm gonna fight with him
因为很多事情和他争斗
about a lot of things over the years.
所以为什么不以一次我们合作的斗争
So why not start with a fight
作为开始呢
where we're both on the same side?
好吧  我信任你
Okay, I trust you.
那就好
Good.
杰西卡  你有时间吗
Jessica, you have a minute?
如果你是来告诉我为何
I do if you're here to tell me
罗伯特・赞恩会在大堂里
why Robert Zane is sitting in the lobby
等着见你  那我就有
with an appointment to see you.
因为我很确定他是不会
'Cause I'm pretty sure he's not taking time
利用忙碌的早上讨论装饰品的
out of his busy morning to talk about centerpieces.
他是不会
No, he's not.
他是来共同代理凯尔顿案的
He is here to co-counsel the Kelton case.
你是说我明确让你撤销的那个案子吗
You mean the case I explicitly told you to drop?
我是说那个你认为会造成巨额的
I mean the case that you said would cost a fortune to fund
你并不想承担的开销的案子
and you didn't wanna lay out that kind of money for.
我不想承担是因为这个案子会输
I didn't want to lay it out because this case is a loser.
而我想告诉你不会输
And I'm telling you it's not.
而且就算会输  我也将损失消除了
And even if it is, I just took away our downside.
通过背着我去找我们最大的竞争对手吗
By going behind my back to our biggest competitor.
你是在说你害怕罗伯特・赞恩吗
Are you telling me that you're scared of Robert Zane?
我要不怕是我傻
I'd be a fool if I wasn't.
你要不怕是你傻
And you're a fool if you're not.
我们让那个人走进我们地盘
We let that man into our house,
就只有天知道他会干出什么事了
there's no telling what he'll do.
你知道吗  杰西卡
You know what, Jessica?
如果哈维这么做了  你会很生气
If Harvey had done this, you'd be pissed,
但你最终会允许他那样做
but you'd let him do it anyway.
你也许和他一样拽
And you may be as cocky as him,
但你并不是哈维
but you are not Harvey.
你说对了  对不起
No, you're right. I'm sorry.
我想我应该直接去告诉罗伯特
I guess I'll just go tell Robert
我们无法合作这个案子了
that we won't be working together on this after all.
你很清楚如果你现在这么跟他说
You know damn well if we tell him that now,
会让我看起来很软弱
I look weak.
那也许我确实和哈维一样厉害
So maybe I am as good as Harvey.
有时那并不是一件好事
Well, sometimes that's not a good thing.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去找回一些该死的强势
To get some goddamn strength back.
那你就这么办吧
Then go ahead and do it.
我不只会把你关进小黑屋
I won't just take you to the woodshed.
我会留你在那  等死
I'll leave you there, dead.
看来你在我的办公室
Well, looks like you're making yourself comfortable
还挺舒服
in my offices.
说到椅子的舒适性
About as comfortable as possible in these chairs.
你听说过腰部支持这种功能吗
You ever hear of lumbar support?
我懂了  你喜欢简单实用的
I get it. You like stodgy and functional.
但这些毕竟是我的椅子
But these are my chairs,
就像这是我的案子
just like this is my case.
你到这里来做什么  杰西卡
What exactly are you doing here, Jessica?
我来告诉你这案子的收益一半归我们
I'm here to tell you we're taking half the contingency.
那我也回个信  我给你们1/3
And I'm here to respond. I'm giving you 1/3.
这案子是我们给你的
We brought this case to you.
因为你们觉得这是个烫手的山芋
After you found it in a box crying for its mama.
而且  费用全部由我负担
Plus, I'm footing the bill,
所以收益也没什么好讨论的
which means this fee discussion is over.
或许收益可以就讨论到这儿
Well, this fee discussion may be over,
但关于权力的讨论才刚开始
but the power discussion is just getting started.
你根本不在乎钱的事吧
You don't give a shit about the money, do you?
在这个案子上
On this particular case,
我在意的只是不让你为所欲为
all I give a shit about is keeping you in check.
也就是说  在整个处理案件的期间
Which means, for the duration of this matter,
你得把迈克・罗斯当作合伙人看待
you will be treating Mike Ross like a partner.
你这是开玩笑吧
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
那小子胡子都没长全呢
That boy barely shaves.
就算他还包着尿布我也不管
I don't care if he's still in diapers.
他代表着我的律所
He's representing my firm,
也就代表着我
which means he's representing me.
你看到他  就像看到我一样
You look at him, you see me.
你这个要求可不小
You're asking for a hell of a lot.
那你就把脚从我桌上拿开
Then take your wingtips off my table
离开这间办公室
and walk 'em out the door,
因为这是我的案子
because this is my case
你要么按我说的做  要么就滚蛋
and you either do it my way or you don't do it at all.
我爱死你了
I love you.
路易  今天不是我生日
Louis, it's not my birthday.
我知道  但我知道你很不满意
I know, but I know that you weren't happy
哈维薪酬事件时
with the position I put you in
我把你推入的境地
regarding Harvey's compensation,
所以我想来确认我们之间没什么问题
so I just wanted to make sure that you and I were okay.
说实话  你想知道我真实想法吗
Actually, you wanna know the truth?
此时此刻  我是很不开心
Right at this second, I'm not okay.
那请告诉我
Then please tell me,
我要怎么做才能让你开心
what can I do to make it okay?
你以后再也不要让我
You can start by never putting me
身处那种境地了
in a position like that again.
我不会了
I won't.
杰克  我得和你谈谈
Jack, I need to talk to you.
好  路易  有什么可以帮到你
Sure, Louis, what can I do for you?
你可以认为我已经退出你和哈维的战争了
Well, you can consider me out of your war with Harvey.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
意思是我不喜欢我之前的行为
I'm saying that I don't like what I did,
从现在开始  我不想掺和这件事了
and from now on, I don't want anything to do with it.
我无所谓  路易
Fine by me, Louis.
在我看来  我赢定哈维了
As far as I'm concerned, I won my war with Harvey.
这是你的办公室吗
This is your office?
为什么是这种语气
Why do you say it like that?
-什么语气  -一脸嫌弃
- Like what? - With disgust.
因为哈维的办公室里都是
'Cause Harvey's got autographed basketballs
明星签名的篮球和古董唱片
and vintage records,
而你只有一张男人鞋的照片
and you've got a photograph of a guy's shoes.
你最好小心
Well, you better be careful
否则大脚中士胡卡
or Sergeant Hulka with the big toe
会用尽全力踹你屁股
is gonna see how far he can stick it up your ass.
你在说什么鬼
What the hell are you talking about?
《杂牌军东征》
Stripes.
我刚引用了里面的对白
I'm just quoting Stripes.
那是一部电影
It's a movie.
哈维和我常常这样对话
Harvey and I do this all the time.
我不懂你和他之前玩的儿童游戏
Look, I don't know what kind of teenage nonsense
我也不爱玩
you got going on with him, but I don't do that shit.
好吧
Okay.
我打算去趟疗养院
I'm going to visit the facility.
十分钟后楼下大堂见
Meet you down in the lobby in ten.
这么说你和杰西卡谈得还顺利
I take it that means that things went well with Jessica?
对  她罢手了  而我要做的只是
Yep, she signed off, and all I had to do was
答应把你当作成熟平等的合伙人对待
agree to treat you as a full and equal partner.
那肯定对你打击不小
Whoa, that must have hurt.
才不是  我不是真的答应她
Eh, it didn't hurt a bit, 'cause I didn't mean it with her,
我也不会真的那么对你
and I'm not gonna do it with you.
十分钟后见
See you in 10.
最好十五分钟
Better make that 15.
听说你在找我
Heard you're looking for me.
对  因为我想把这个给你
I was, because I wanted to give you this.
这是什么
What's that?
去韦斯特切斯特乡村俱乐部的路线
Directions to Westchester Country Club.
为什么要给我这个
Why are you giving them to me?
因为我不希望你错过了11:30
Because I don't want you to be late to your 11:30 tee time
[前美国职业篮球运动员  NBA历史上著名的大前锋之一]
和查尔斯・巴克利的那场球
with Charles Barkley.
我要和查尔斯・巴克利打高尔夫
I'm playing golf with Charles Barkley?
如果你按时到的话  是的
If you get there on time, you are.
如果你迟到了  他会乱挥大杆
If not and he starts whacking at shit with his big club,
搞不好还会杀人呢
he might kill someone.
那你就错过了好戏
You'll miss the whole thing.
你以为我不知道你的小算盘吗
You think I don't know what you're doing?
你在巴结我  因为突然间
You're sucking up to me 'cause all of a sudden
你意识到我是个不可小觑的人物
you realized I'm someone to be reckoned with.
你说的没错
That is what I'm doing.
可你是个高尔夫好手又是巴克利的球迷
But you're a big golfer and a bigger Barkley fan,
我想可以借此机会让我们不计前嫌重新开始
and I thought we could use this to get off to a fresh start.
只有一个问题  哈维
Here's the problem, Harvey.
我根本不喜欢查尔斯・巴克利
I don't give a shit about Charles Barkley,
而你也不喜欢我
and you don't give a shit about me.
听我说  这是个示好的举动
Listen to me. This is a gesture.
接受吧
Take it.
我不会接受的
I'm not gonna take it,
我告诉你为什么
and I'm gonna tell you why.
因为你从来不把我当成伙伴
Because you've never treated me like a peer.
你只把我当作是竞争对手
You've only ever treated me like competition.
我很努力了
I'm trying very hard here.
别白费劲了  我不感兴趣
Well, you can stop trying, because I'm not interested.
斯佩克特先生  我发誓他跟我说
Mr. Specter, I swear he told me
他是查尔斯・巴克利的死忠球迷
he was a huge Charles Barkley fan.
我相信  但问题是他撒谎了
I'm sure he did, but the problem is he lied,
你该意识到的
and you should've known it.
不管你要做什么都推后
Whatever you're doing, put it back.
-我需要你  -不行啊
- I need you. - I can't.
什么叫不行  我们就要开战了
What do you mean, you can't? We're about to go to war.
我是说我自己就有一场硬仗要打
I mean, I'm about to go to war myself.
你到底在说什么鬼
What the hell are you talking about?
我要对付凯尔顿保险公司
I'm taking a case against Kelton Insurance.
我现在要去见客户了
I gotta go meet the client right now.
谁同意你接这个案子的
Who the hell authorized that?
杰西卡
Jessica.
现在你不找我找杰西卡了
You went to Jessica instead of me?
我谁也没找  好吗
I didn't go to anyone, all right?
我接下了案子之后她来找我的
She came to me after I took it.
我告诉你  这案子你必须推后
Well, I'm telling you, you're gonna have to postpone it.
哈维  这个案子很重要
Harvey, this case is important.
我告诉你什么才重要
I'll tell you what's important.
这律所的一个合伙人在针对我
I got a partner at this firm coming at me.
我接这个案子的时候还不知道这事
Well, I didn't know that when I committed to this.
怎么回事  我们不是在大堂碰头吗
What the hell? I thought we were meeting in the lobby.
你逗我吧  这案子你和他一起做
You gotta be kidding me. Your case is with him?
说的没错  是和我一起
You're damn right it's with me.
我们还要去给人留个好印象呢
And we have a first impression to make.
我不知道你是怎么教他法律的
I don't know what kind of law you're teaching around here,
但我的老师告诉我  律师要守时
but where I come from, you show up on time.
我们走
Let's go.
你想去
You wanna go?
那就去吧
Go.
杰西卡  有事吗
Jessica, what can I do for you?
你曾找我咨询法律问题
You came to me for some legal advice.
现在轮到我来咨询你了
Now I'm coming to you for yours.
我能收你咨询费吗
Do I get to charge you for it?
你已经收了  除非你突然
You already do, unless you suddenly
开始自掏腰包付法学院的学费了
started paying for law school out of your own pocket.
那就免费吧
Free of charge it is.
我希望你看看这个
I want you to look this over
告诉我里面有没有不妥之处
and tell me if we have any exposure.
好  但这不是协议
Okay, but this isn't a deal.
这是篇演讲稿
This is a speech.
我知道
I'm aware of that,
但格温・巴恩斯很固执己见
but Gwen Barnes is quite opinionated,
我不希望她说出
and I don't want her to say something
招来诉讼的话
that might get her sued.
格温多琳・巴恩斯医生
Dr. Gwendolyn Barnes?
你和她有矛盾吗
Do you have a problem with her?
没有  我有多长时间
No, not at all. How much time do I have?
没有时限
Take as long as you want.
只要等我来要的时候
Just make sure whenever I come back for it,
搞定了就好
it's done.
你来干什么
What are you doing in here?
我是来道歉的
I came to apologize.
你不需要道歉
You don't need to apologize.
我做得过火了
I was out of line.
索罗夫是个混蛋  那不是你的错
Soloff's an asshole, and it wasn't your fault.
不  你没错  的确是我的错
No, you were right. It was my fault.
木已成舟
Well, what's done is done.
你不介意的话  让我单独思考一会儿吧
If you don't mind, I need to think right now.
斯佩克特先生  可木还没成舟呢
I'm sorry, Mr. Specter, but what's done is not done.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我说过  我是你的后盾
I told you, I got your back.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
那个混蛋第三大客户的简历
It's the bio of that asshole's third biggest client.
-然后呢  -你看他的出身地
- And? - Look where he's from.
我很感激你们能找到这里来
I appreciate you coming all the way down here,
但上次你们来找我的时候
but the last time you came to me,
让我耐心等待  那可是一周前的事了
you told me to sit tight, and that was a week ago.
艾玛  我不懂
Emma, I don't understand.
你希望怎样
What did you expect?
我希望你们理解被晾在一边
I expected you to understand what it feels like
是什么感觉
to be left hanging.
我们要是不理解那感觉
Because if we can't understand that,
等事情变棘手时
what's to stop us from cutting and running
还有什么能阻止我们临阵脱逃呢
when things get tough?
那你们说什么能阻止你们
And what is gonna stop you?
我知道什么事会阻止我
I know what's gonna stop me.
第一年  你每天都在回想
First year...you think about it every day.
情景重现
You relive it.
无论你做什么
Doesn't matter what you do.
都没法将它赶出脑海
You can't get it out of your head.
人们会告诉你这是上帝的安排
People tell you it's part of God's plan.
也许他们没错  但这并没有让你
Maybe they're right, but it doesn't stop you
消除每次听到这句话时
from wanting to punch them in the face
揍他们一拳的冲动
every time they say it.
然后时间流逝
Then time passes,
过了两三年
two, three years.
甚至你可能都开始觉得  一切恢复了平常
Maybe you even start to feel normal.
或许你开始相信
Maybe you start to believe that
这件事并不会
maybe this thing won't actually
对你未来的人生留下伤痕
scar you for the rest of your life.
但突然有一天
But then one day,
某件事让你回想起来
something reminds you.
一首歌或是一股味道
A song or a... or a smell.
触动了那根神经  突然之间
And it touches that nerve, and all of a sudden,
你又回到了听到消息的那天
it's the day you got that news all over again.
你也经历过类似的事情吗
So you have gone through something like this yourself?
我不仅经历过
I haven't just gone through it.
那是我成为律师的全部原因
It's the entire reason that I became a lawyer.
虽然我们让你等了等
And as far as it taking as long as it did,
因为研究细节得花点时间
it took a while to work out the particulars.
但我向你保证
But I can assure you,
等待是值得的
it's worth the wait,
因为在你眼前
because this right here,
就是全明星队  专为你而战
this is an all-star team, and we're playing for you.
那么
Well...
我在哪儿签字
Where do I sign?
好了  这件事处理完了
All right, we got that taken care of.
接下来要做什么
Next step?
安排和解会面
Set up a settlement conference.
说的没错
Got that right.
你是说"说的没错  队友"
You mean "You got that right, partner."
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
那话可是你说的
You're the one that said it yourself.
我们俩是全明星队
You and me, we're the all-star team.
全明星是我  你是那个队伍
I meant I was the all-star. You're the team.
那这个案子里  这个队伍
Oh, so I guess in this case the team
刚投中了决胜球啊
just hit the game-winning jumper.
这么跟你说吧  队伍
I got news for you, team,
比赛还没开始呢
the game hasn't even started yet.
迈克  说真的  刚才
Mike, seriously, back there,
你童年的那些事  我之前都不太理解
about your childhood, I didn't really get it before.
你曾经历不顺
You got dealt a bad hand,
但努力克服困难走到了今天
and you pulled yourself up by your bootstraps,
我很赞赏
and I respect that.
谢谢  罗伯特
Thanks, Robert.
-你可以叫我"爸"了  -真的吗
- You can call me "Dad." - Really?
假的
No.
你知道我说的是我爸吧
So you know we're talking about my father, right,
他已经去世了
who's no longer alive?
-我忘了  -你忘了
- Yeah, I forgot that. - You forgot that?
那可是你夸我的基础前提啊
The basis of your compliment in the first place?
再有趣的东西也能被你搞无趣  是不是
You suck the fun out of everything, don't you?
完成得很快啊
You did this quickly.
你交给我工作  我做完了而已
You gave me a job to do, and I did it.
那你为什么放在我桌上
And why did you leave it on my desk
而不是当面交给我
instead of bringing it to me directly?
我只想让你能先看一看
I just wanted to give you a chance to look it over.
这跟我让你做的其实是检查
And does that have something to do with the fact
而不是重写的事实
that I asked you to check it for exposure
有什么关系吗
and not rewrite it?
我知道我可能做的超过了任务范畴
I know, I may have overstepped my assignment.
但巴恩斯医生是纽约大医院里
It's just Dr. Barnes is the first black female
第一位黑人女性外科主任
chief of surgery at a major New York hospital.
她面对四处的歧视
She faced discrimination at every turn,
依然完成了工作
and she still got the job done,
她不需要高谈阔论来传达这一点
so she doesn't need soaring language to communicate that.
我会把你的话转达给巴恩斯医生的
I'll tell Dr. Barnes you said that.
所以你接受我的改写
So you're accepting my changes?
我会很高兴的拿给她看
I'll present them to her with my blessing.
看看她怎么想
We'll see what she thinks.
杰西卡
Jessica, um...
如果你哪天代理巴恩斯医生的案子
if you ever have a case with Dr. Barnes,
我很愿意参与
I would love to be a part of it.
我有更好的主意
I have a better idea.
你跟我一起去听演讲怎么样
Why don't you come to the speech with me?
所以我们才需要想个办法
That is exactly why we need to figure out a way
帮你进入康卡斯特董事会
to get you on the board of directors of Comcast.
希望如此吧
From your lips to God's ears.
杰克  抱歉  能跟你谈谈吗
Jack, I'm sorry. Can I speak to you for a second?
我们正忙着呢
Uh, we're kind of in the middle of something.
只要一分钟  是律所事务
It'll only take a minute. It's firm business.
恐怕由不得你选
I'm afraid it's not optional.
抱歉打扰了
I'm sorry to interrupt.
我是哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter, by the way,
皮尔逊-斯佩克特律所合伙人
of Pearson Specter.
我马上回来
This will only take a second.
你以为我不知道你在干什么吗
You think I don't know what you're doing?
你想挖走我的客户
You're trying to poach my client.
你怎么会觉得我想这么做
What makes you think I'm trying to do that?
"哈维・斯佩克特  皮尔逊-斯佩克特律所合伙人"
Please, "Harvey Specter of Pearson Specter."
我告诉你
Let me tell you something,
那家伙做我客户十年了
guy's been my client for ten years.
他不会为你这种人离开我
He's not leaving me for the likes of you.
那我猜这里没什么事了
Then I guess our business here is done.
怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
没什么  你可以走了
Nothing's going on. You're free.
实际上  我还会送你回去
In fact, I'll walk you back.
看啊
Oh, look at that.
查尔斯・巴克利是在跟
Is that Charles Barkley taking a selfie
你那个刚巧在费城长大  经历过巴克利时代的
with your loyal client who happened to have grown up
忠诚的客户玩自拍吗
in Philadelphia during the Barkley era?
你也许不在乎查尔斯
Look, you might not give a shit about Charles,
但他绝对在乎
but he sure as hell does.
你这个贱人
You son of a bitch.
抱歉  杰克  你能再说一遍吗
I'm sorry, Jack. Could you repeat that?
我抢走你客户的声音太大  我都听不清你说什么
I couldn't hear you over the sound of me taking your client.
那让我大声说一遍  这事没完
Then let me say it louder. This isn't over.
最好没完  因为你还有四位
It better be, because you've got four other clients
来自芝加哥  波士顿  洛杉矶和休斯顿的客户
from Chicago, Boston, Los Angeles, and Houston.
你也许不认识那些著名球员
And you may not know who those famous ballers are,
但我认识
but I do.
威尔  詹妮弗
Will, Jennifer,
感谢你们出席如此仓促的会面
thank you for seeing us on such short notice.
你们确实给我们客户招来一场诉讼
Well, you did serve our client with a lawsuit.
不过  我们有笔交易给你们
Nevertheless, we have an offer for you.
逗我吧
You've gotta be kidding me.
你把我们千里迢迢喊过来就给我们看这个
You called us all the way down here for this?
我都不屑用它当厕纸
I wouldn't wipe my ass with this.
罗伯特  我们可不这么看
Well, Robert, we don't look at it that way.
那你是怎么看的  威尔
How exactly do you look at it, Will?
我们把这当做是给两只
We look at it as a gift to a couple of vultures
想从一桩旧案的骨头上撕肉吃的秃鹫的礼物
trying to pick the flesh off the bones of an old case.
每个有所隐瞒的律师
That is what every lawyer
都是这么说的
who has had something to hide has ever said.
这也不能改变
And it doesn't change the fact
你的客户害死二百人的事实
that your client killed 200 people.
我们对上个律师是这么说的  现在还是这句话
Then we're gonna tell you what we told the last attorney.
你要是想上法庭  此后十年
You go to trial, you'll be buried in paperwork
你都会被埋在文件堆里
for the next ten years.
换作是昨天
Well, if this were yesterday,
我们也许会被吓到
then we might be rattled by that.
但是后来  我们得到了新信息
But since then, new information has come to light.
什么新信息
And what new information is that?
这是我的律所的雇员名单
This is a list of everyone who works at my firm.
And this is a list of everyone that works at mine.
我们可不是什么在商场外办公
You see, we're not some solo practitioner
雇佣兼职助手的个体律师
with a part-time paralegal working out of a mall.
我的助理律师的意思是
What my associate is getting at is
我们是两家大律所
we're two huge law firms,
专为告倒你们而设计
perfectly designed to kick your ass.
我不在乎你们律所有多少人
I don't care how many people work at your firms.
总得有人付他们薪水
Someone needs to pay their salaries.
如果你接这个案子
And if you're working on this,
当心付不出薪水
you're not doing that.
那么二百亿对冲基金
Then doesn't it come in handy
就派上用场了
to have a $20-billion hedge fund footing the bill?
所以  你们要么再加几个零
So you can either add a bunch of zeroes to this bullshit offer,
要么我们法庭见
or we'll see you in court.
介意我问你个问题吗
Mind if I ask you a question?
如果是想利用我的关系
If it's about using my connections
请史提夫・汪达来你的婚礼唱歌
to get Stevie Wonder to play at your wedding,
我已经试过了
I already tried.
为什么不告诉我对冲基金的事
Why didn't you tell me about the hedge fund?
钱从哪里来
Well, what difference does it make
有什么区别吗
where we get our money from?
没什么区别
It doesn't make a difference,
只是你完全没跟我提过
except for the fact you didn't tell me.
那你生什么气呢
What are you getting so bent out of shape for?
我们干得挺漂亮啊
We landed a punch back there.
我们  还是你
We landed a punch or you did?
什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
先是说我是你的"助理律师"
First you call me "Associate" in front of opposing counsel,
而后还让我发现有事瞒着我
and now I find out you're keeping things from me.
-听着  -我们到底是不是一个团队
- Look-- - I'm just saying, are we a team or not?
我当时叫你助理律师
I called you what I called you in there
是因为他们想见到说了算的人
because they want to see someone in charge.
看着我们俩  他们会认为是我
And looking at the two of us, they're gonna think it's me.
我没想着告诉你基金的事
And I didn't think about telling you about Arcadian
因为这是你不在的时候我想出来的
because I came up with that when you weren't there.
我得说  我也有过同样的主意
For the record, I had the same idea.
我去找你之前  就找过对冲基金了
I went to a hedge fund before I even came to you.
祝贺你
Well, congratulations.
如果你像我一样搞定了基金的人
If you had closed them like I closed my guys,
我就不用站在这儿自我辩解了
I wouldn't be standing here explaining myself.
等那些跳梁小丑回复后再聊
So let's talk when we hear back from these clowns.
现在笑一个吧  你刚才棒极了
And put a smile on your face. You kicked ass in there.
杰克  有事吗
Jack, what can I do for you?
你可以把你的狗拴好
You can get your dog on a leash.
什么
Excuse me?
哈维刚刚抢走我的一位客户
Harvey just stole one of my clients.
我想把他要回来
I want him back.
你有证据吗
Do you have proof?
有  他故意让查尔斯・巴克利
Yeah, he orchestrated some bullshit run-in
跟他偶遇
with Charles Barkley,
然后奇迹发生了  我的客户要换律师
and miraculously my client, he needs to make a change.
这不是证据
Well, that's not proof.
我不需要证据  我知道他做了什么
I don't need proof. I know what the hell he did.
我也知道你和路易
Just like I know what you and Louis did
为了通过你的薪金提案做了什么
to pass your compensation resolution.
如果我有证据
And if I had proof of that,
我们现在就不是在聊这个
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
而是在做你的离职面谈了
We'd be having your exit interview.
你是要指责我
You gonna sling accusations at me,
还是控制好你的这只狗
or you gonna get your dog Harvey under control?
因为如果你控制不了他
'Cause if you can't control him,
也许你也不应该控制这家律所
maybe you shouldn't be in control of this firm.
控制他
Control him?
我告诉你  杰克
Let me tell you something, Jack.
你跟哈维作对  就是在跟我作对
When you went after Harvey, you went after me,
所以一开始就是我
which is why I'm the one
派他去对付你
that sent him after you in the first place.
我刚提出了让所有合伙人都受益的提案
And I just put more money in every other partner's pocket,
所以你最好听我的
which means you better listen to me when I talk.
耍手段让合伙人们支持你做事这一招
There's only so many times you can pull some shady shit
用不了几次就不会再好使了
to get something done with the partners.
所以如果你想挑战我
So you want to take me on?
我乐意奉陪
I'm right here.
忙什么呢
What are you working on?
凯尔顿的案子
The Kelton case.
我正想问你呢
I've been meaning to ask you,
和我爸爸处得怎么样
how's it going with my dad?
挺好
It's fine.
一切...都挺好
It's, uh-- it's going fine.
挺好
Mm-hmm, it's fine.
我知道"挺好"是什么意思
I know what "It's fine" means.
"挺好"意味着根本不好
"It's fine" means it's not fine,
而你意识到我是对的
and you're realizing that I was right
你错了
and you were wrong,
他真的非常不好相处
and he is a giant pain in the ass.
瑞秋  我从没说过我们不会起争端
Rachel, I never said there wouldn't be arguments.
我只是说这些争端最终会让我们更加亲近
I just said ultimately they'd bring us closer.
我知道  你确实是这样说的
I know, you did.
我没想让你烦恼
I'm not trying to cause trouble.
我只是在卖萌
I was just trying to be charming and delightful.
谢谢
Thanks.
只是...
It's just--
你爸爸的尊重对我很重要
It's important to me that your dad respects me.
我最能确定的一件事就是
If there is one thing that I am certain of,
我父亲是尊重你的
it's that my father respects you.
明白吗
Okay?
哈维  你是对的
Harvey, you were right.
这是我吃过的最好吃的牛排之一
That's one of the best steaks I ever had.
你还是告诉我你为什么带我来这里吧
How about you tell me why you actually brought me here?
一个人就不能带自己的客户出来吃顿晚餐吗
Can't a man just take his client out to dinner?
别人可能  但你肯定有所图
A man can, but you need something,
而我刚刚已经帮过你那个小忙了
and I just did you that little favor.
那可不算帮忙
That wasn't a favor.
我花了十五分钟和一个费城来的笨蛋拍合照
I took 15 minutes of pictures with some dipshit from Philadelphia.
还不算帮忙吗
That's not a favor?
那只是热身
That was an appetizer.
我需要你让魔术师  伯德
I need you to get Magic, Bird,
指"魔术师"埃尔文・约翰逊  拉里・伯德
哈基姆和迈克尔
Hakeem, and Michael
指哈基姆-奥拉朱旺和迈克尔・乔丹
也这样做
to do the same thing.
你可真有趣  你在开玩笑对吧
You're a funny guy. You're kidding, right?
那天晚上你给我打电话的时候
Did I ask you if you were kidding me
我问你是不是在开玩笑了吗
when you called me that night?
你让我跟你签约  我已经签了
You asked me to sign with you, and I did.
我还说我有一天会要你还人情
And I also said that I would need something from you someday,
而和一个76人的笨蛋粉丝拍张自拍
and taking selfies with some dipshit Sixers fan
可不算还上这个人情了
isn't gonna cut it.
哈维  你得和这个索罗夫讲和
Harvey, you need to chill with this Soloff thing.
否则每一天你走进办公室
If not, every single day you go into the office,
他都会在想办法给你背后捅刀子
he's gonna be trying to stab you in the back.
我不是来听你的建议的  查尔斯
I'm not here to get your advice, Charles.
我是来让你帮我的
I'm here to get you to help me.
我是不会把梦之队招到一起来帮你的
I'm not getting the Dream Team back together.
只要你想办就一定能办到
It can happen if you make it happen.
我不会办的
It's not gonna happen.
而且我认识的那个哈维是不会让我这样做的
And the Harvey I know would never ask me to do it.
多给些小费
Listen, leave a big tip.
人们以为这顿饭是我出钱呢
People think I'm paying for the meal.
不管你在干什么都先放下
Put down whatever you're doing.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
你是在和一个冠名合伙人说话
You're talking to a name partner,
我建议你放尊重点
so I suggest you do it with a little respect.
我来找你一起去打击哈维的要害
I'm showing respect by coming to you
已经是尊重你了
to hit Harvey where it hurts.
我告诉你了  我不想扯进
I told you, I don't want anything to do
你和哈维的战争里
with your war with Harvey.
你已经扯进来了
You already have something to do with it.
而你说你不介意我退出
And you said you didn't care if I backed out.
我才不管我说过什么呢
I don't give a shit what I said.
你已经选边站队了  回不了头了
You picked a side. There's no going back.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
我不会干这件事的  这太过火了  杰克
I'm not doing it. This is way too far, Jack.
不  我们从一开始就该这样干
No, it's what we should have done in the first place.
反正无所谓了
Well, you know, it doesn't even matter,
因为你根本不能提起这样的决议
because you can't introduce a resolution like this,
这有违律所章程
'cause it violates the bylaws.
那你就需要私下里使些手段
Then you need to do some underhanded shit
让它不违反章程
to make it unviolate the bylaws.
我已经告诉过你了
And I already told you
我不会再做那样的事了
that I'm not doing anything like that again.
太糟糕了  因为你已经干过一次了
Too bad, because you did it once.
如果你不想让我告诉别人
And if you don't want me telling anybody about it,
你就得接着干
you'll do it again.
早上好  路易
Good morning, Louis.
看起来你忙了不少事
Well, looks like you've been busy.
是的
I have.
这是克伦肖案的取证记录
Here's the Crenshaw depo,
这是基尔希的行程安排
and this is the Kirsch itinerary,
还有你的音乐盒
and here's your music box.
你为什么要把我的礼物还回来
Why are you giving my gift back?
因为你送我这份礼物的时候保证说
Because it was a gift you gave me with a promise
你绝不会再置我于那样的境地了
never to put me in a position like that again.
-我确实没有  -但你将来会
- And I haven't. - But you will.
而且不要撒谎说你不会
And don't tell me you won't,
因为我昨天听到你和杰克・索罗夫的小阴谋了
because I overheard your little scheme with Jack Soloff.
那你就应该听到我让他见鬼去吧
Then you obviously heard me tell him to go to hell.
不  路易  我听到他告诉你
No, Louis, I heard him tell you
不管你愿不愿意都得参加这场战争
that you're in this war whether you like it or not.
然后他大摇大摆走出门
And then he walked out that door,
而你一个字都没说
and you didn't say a damn thing.
我发誓我会信守诺言
I swear I'm gonna keep my promise.
我不会去对付哈维的
I am not going after Harvey.
你以为我这是为了保护哈维吗
You think this is about me protecting Harvey?
我这是在保护我自己
This is about me protecting me.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
那天晚上哈维来找我
Harvey came to me the other night
让我承认我知道你干了什么
to get me to admit that I knew what you did.
他去找你了吗
He came to you?
去我家
In my home.
我不得不站在那里  在他面前
And I had to stand there and lose my integrity
为了你说违心的话
in front of him for you.
天啊  他真的在那样做
Oh, my God, he's really doing it.
做什么
Doing what?
薪金方案投票以后
After the compensation vote,
哈维和我吵了一架
Harvey and I got into a fight,
我告诉他我刚刚夺走了
and I told him that I'd just taken away
他最在乎的一样东西
the one thing he values most:
他的钱
his money.
然后他告诉我他会夺走
He then tells me that he's gonna come
我最在乎的一样东西
after the one thing that I value most.
我
Me.
是的
Yes.
他告诉我  某天  我走进办公室
Told me that one day I would come to this office,
会发现你不见了
you'd be gone,
而我会知道是他从我身边把你夺走的
and I'd know that it was him who took you away from me.
他说他会把我夺走吗
He said he was gonna take me away?
听我说
Listen to me.
我发誓  我绝不会再那样对你了
I swear I will never do that to you again.
但请不要离开我
But please do not leave me.
我不会离开你的  路易
I'm not leaving you, Louis.
你收到这个了吗
You get this?
当然  撤案动议
Sure did. Motion to dismiss.
是的  你知道这意味着什么  对吧
Yeah. You know what this means, right?
我们把他们逼入绝境  他们害怕了
We got 'em on the ropes. They're scared.
所以明天早上
Which is why I scheduled a hearing
我跟赫尔南德斯法官定下了听证会
with Judge Hernandez for tomorrow morning.
她会驳回这鬼东西
She's gonna dismiss this bullshit,
我还会直接让她去开庭
and I'm gonna get her to move straight to trial.
罗伯特  这主意可不好
Uh, Robert, that's a bad idea.
为什么
What are you talking about?
他们出拳  我们就接招
They throw a jab, we answer with a right cross.
是的  如果现在开庭  我们就会得到判决
Yes, if we go to trial now, we get a decision,
但如果三个月后再开庭  我们就可以轰动一时
but if we go in three months, we get a knockout.
你在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
州长桌上摆着一份法案
There's a bill on the governor's desk
等着通过
waiting to be passed.
是提升惩罚性损失赔偿的上限的法案
It lifts the cap on punitive damages.
他还没批准是有原因的
There's a reason he hasn't signed it yet.
美国医学会盯着他呢
The A.M.A. is up his ass.
我们现在动手
We go now.
凯尔顿保险公司的首席执行官的合同到期了
The C.E.O. of Kelton Insurance's contract is up.
他不会想因为被控杀人
He doesn't want to be renegotiating
上报纸头条
while he's on the front page of the journal
害得自己要重谈合约
being accused of killing people.
那种威胁可以让那些人
That threat takes these people
将赔偿从一千美元提高到五千美元
from $1,000 per person to $5,000,
但如果我们真上了法庭
but if we actually go to trial--
如果我们上法庭  我们可能什么都得不到
If we go to trial, we may get nothing.
我不想再谈了
And I'm finished having this conversation.
我看出来了  我们不是搭档
So now I see where we stand. We're not partners.
我只是个助理律师
I'm just the associate.
只有你说了算
You're the one calling the shots.
我想第一次谈的时候
I thought I made that clear
我就已经说得很清楚了
from the second we started this thing.
现在回复这项动议  搞定我的动议
Now answer this motion, get my motion done,
明天到法庭来
and be in court tomorrow morning,
因为无论你愿不愿意  我会做到
because this is gonna happen whether you like it or not.
搞什么鬼
Oh--what the hell?
什么搞什么鬼
What the hell what?
你撞翻了我的咖啡
You spilled my coffee.
是你撞到我
You ran into me.
我不在乎谁撞到谁
I don't care who ran into who.
这是我的办公室  你不打算说声"对不起"吗
This is my office. How about a little "Excuse me"?
好  哈维  对不起
Oh, okay, Harvey. Excuse me.
请自愿帮我付干洗的账单
Feel free to send me the bill for dry cleaning.
我可以付这里其他一切费用
I'm paying for everything else around here.
唐娜  现在不是时候
Donna, now is not a good time.
我不管
I don't care.
我可不是你报复路易的筹码
I'm not a prize to be used to get revenge on Louis.
你在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你要否认你对他说
Are you gonna deny you told him
你要把我夺回来吗
that you were gonna take me back?
我没那么说
That is not what I said.
别跟我耍律师那一套
No, do not lawyer me,
因为也许那不是你的原话
because it may not be exactly what you said,
但别告诉我你没有暗示过
but don't try to tell me it wasn't what you meant.
-唐娜  -还有  你为什么会觉得
- Donna... - And another thing, what makes you think
如果我会离开路易
if I were ever to leave Louis
还会回到你身边
that I would ever, ever come back to you?
斯佩克特先生  我知道现在不是时候
Mr. Specter, I know this is a bad time,
但我必须提醒你
but I have to remind you that--
我知道  杰西卡要见我
I know! Jessica wants to see me.
唐娜  我能跟你谈谈吗
Donna, hey, can I talk to you for a second?
现在真不是时候
It's actually not a good time right this second.
这很重要
It's important.
我只想知道
I just need to know
哈维跟赫尔南德法官关系还是很好吗
if Harvey is still tight with Judge Hernandez.
干什么
Why?
我要她为我把听证会延期
I need her to postpone a hearing for me.
知道吗  迈克
You know what, Mike?
如果你要哈维帮忙
If you want something from Harvey,
你就自己去跟他说
you're gonna have to ask him yourself.
你想见我
You wanted to see me?
十二小时前我就叫你来
That was 12 hours ago.
我那时正在安排事情
I was putting some things in order.
安排什么
What things in order,
从杰克・索罗夫那偷更多客户吗
stealing more of Jack Soloff's clients?
说实话  是的
As a matter of fact, yes.
见鬼  哈维
God damn it, Harvey.
杰西卡  我去找他  努力想和解
Jessica, I went in there. I tried to make peace.
可他却羞辱我
He spat in my face.
我再次努力  他仍旧那样
I tried again. He did it again.
于是我说  我受够了
And I said, "Enough is enough".
那你走就是了  不能偷他的客户啊
Then you walk out the door. You don't steal his clients.
知道吗  这不关你的事
You know what? This doesn't concern you.
是我和杰克的事
This is between me and Jack.
他来找我之前  确实是你和杰克的事
Oh, it was between you and Jack until he came to me,
而我还得包庇你
and I had to cover for you.
你包庇我
You covered for me?
说对了
Goddamn right I did.
我跟他说  从一开始
I told him sending you after him was my idea
就是我派你去的
in the first place.
这不是包庇我
That's not covering for me.
而是包庇你自己
That's covering for you,
因为一开始  这就应该是你的主意
because that should have been your idea in the first place,
而不是背着我  让我们所有的竞争对手
instead of welcoming every competitor we have
都跑到公司来
into our offices behind my back.
你在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我说的是罗伯特・赞恩
I'm talking about Robert Zane
你没有告诉我  就让他过来了
and you bringing him in here without consulting me.
我可没让他来
I didn't bring in shit.
是迈克・罗斯没打招呼就把他叫来了
Mike Ross brought Zane in without asking,
我还得假装知道这件事
and I had to pretend to be on board with that too.
现在你在期待事情向你希望的方向发展
And now you're hoping this leads to what you always wanted.
事情结束了  赞恩走了
This thing's over, Zane goes,
迈克跟他一起走了
and Mike heads out the door with him.
够了
That's enough.
你别再发疯了
You need to get yourself under control right now.
你在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我说的是你有问题
I'm talking about you have a problem,
而这个问题跟我没关系
and it doesn't have anything to do with me.
你暴露了这点是因为
And you just expose it by bringing up
你在妄想迈克・罗斯
some paranoid bullshit about Mike Ross
跟罗伯特・赞恩走了
going with Robert Zane.
因为这一切开始于唐娜离你而去
Because this all started when Donna left you,
而现在你害怕迈克也会离你而去
and now you're afraid that Mike's going to do the same thing.
所以你最好解决一下你对被抛弃的恐惧
So you better get your abandonment issues under control,
因为杰克・索罗夫会一直找麻烦
because Jack Soloff is gonna keep coming,
现在你必须战胜他
and now you're gonna have to put him down.
斯佩克特先生
Mr. Specter,
迈克・罗斯在办公室等你
Mike Ross is waiting for you in your office.
我得跟你谈谈
Hey, I need to talk to you.
现在不要
Not now.
我知道你还在生气  但我需要帮助
I know you're mad from before, but I need a favor.
我说了  现在不要
I said not now.
哈维  你怎么了
Harvey, what's going on with you?
没事  我得喝杯水
Nothing's wrong. I need a glass of water.
怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
好吧  我打911
Okay, I'm dialing 911.
不  别打
No, you're not.
我要打  你可能是心脏病突发
Yes, I am. You could be having a heart attack.
-这不是心脏病突发  -你怎么知道
- It's not a heart attack. - You don't know that.
这是恐慌症
It's a panic attack.
我不想打扰你们的恩爱时刻
Oh, hate to interrupt a special moment,
但我觉得你可能想看看这个
but I thought you might wanna take a gander at this.
那是什么
What the hell is that?
如果你还记得  我们上次的提案
If you recall, our last proposal
减少了风险案件分成
reduced contingent compensation.
而这份提案彻底废除了它
This one wipes it out altogether.
怎么了  不帅气地反击了吗
What's the matter? No snappy comeback?
我读过公司章程  你不能那么做
I've read the bylaws. You can't do that.
你现在要当他的打手了吗
You doing his fighting for him now?
我才不在乎公司章程写了什么
I don't care what the bylaws say.
我有路易的支持
I have Louis's backing.
要么你把客户还给我
So either you give back my client,
要么就和其他所有人一样  达到
or good luck billing 2,500 hours a year
每年2500小时的计费工作时间
like the rest of us.
你尽管提交你的提案等候表决
You go right ahead and put your proposal to a vote.
但是等这个提案通过的时候
But by the time this thing passes,
我早就把你另外四个客户抢走了
I'll have your other four clients.
瞎扯  你不可能已经接触他们了
Bullshit, you couldn't have gotten to them already.
去查吧  他们已经被卷入这场游戏了
Go goddamn check. They're already in play.
这个提案一旦通过
You pass this thing,
你就不可能收到任何报酬了
you won't be billing anything at all.
那样你也没好日子过
You're not gonna get away with that.
错  这场战争不是我开始的
Wrong. I didn't start this,
但将由我来结束
but I'm gonna finish it.
你说我只把你当成竞争对手
And when you said I only ever looked at you as competition,
你错了
you were wrong.
我从没把你放在眼里
I never looked at you as anything at all.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
不好
No.
你刚刚说抢他的客户是真的吗
Is it true what you just said about his clients?
不是  所以我需要你
No, which is why I need you
竭尽所能
to do anything you have to do
让他相信这是真的
to convince him this is happening.
我会搞定的
I'll get it done.
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
这是我家
This is my home.
也是你的办公室
It's also your office.
办公室的入口在那边
And that entrance is right around there.
抱歉  我正在吃晚餐
Now if you'll excuse me, I'm in the middle of my dinner.
我打电话预约治疗  你没回
I called to set an appointment. You didn't call back.
因为我有病人在
Because I had patients.
那我又是什么
And what the hell am I?
你是个几星期没跟我见面的前病人
You're an ex-patient I haven't seen in weeks,
我告诉过你如果你不接受你的秘书
who ignored me when I said that your panic attacks
已经离开的事实  恐慌症永远不会痊愈
wouldn't stop until you accepted the fact
但你无视了我
that your secretary wasn't coming back.
我接受了  而且又请了个秘书
I did accept it, and I had another one anyway.
所以我才来这了
That's why I'm here.
你是说你来这是想再拿点药
You mean you're here to get more pills.
没错
Yes, I am.
我给你的那些药呢
And what happened to the ones I gave you?
我扔了
I threw them out.
扯淡  你根本没扔
Bullshit, you didn't throw them out.
你吃完了
You ran out.
不  我没吃完  我说的是真话
No, I didn't run out. I'm telling you the truth.
好吧  无所谓
Okay, well, it doesn't matter,
因为我是个心理医生  不是药房
because I'm a psychiatrist, not a pharmacy,
如果你需要我的帮助  就按我说的来
and if you want my help, you do it my way.
你得按常规预约治疗时间
You make regular appointments,
并且要遵医嘱
and you commit to doing the work.
如果你再突然出现在我家门口
And you show up at my house unannounced again,
我就报警
I'm calling the police.
十分钟之后你有没有时间
Do you have any time available ten minutes from now?
我想给你点时间先吃完晚餐
I want to give you time to finish your dinner.
车准备好了吗
Is the car ready?
就在楼下  和你一样整装待发
It's downstairs warming up, like you.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我收到了邀请函
Well, I received the invitation
并且注意到
and couldn't help but notice
巴恩斯医生参加了这次活动
that Dr. Barnes is in the program,
你也参加了
and you're in the program too.
没错  我确实参加了
Look at that, I am.
为什么不告诉我这就是你的演讲
Why didn't you tell me it was your speech?
我想要你最诚实的意见
I wanted your honest opinion.
但你没问我的意见
But you didn't ask for my opinion.
你让我检查它是否有不妥当的地方
You asked me to check it for exposure.
我注意到你有一个特点
If there's one thing I've noticed about you,
不管有没有人询问
it's that you give your opinion
你都会给出你的意见
whether it's asked for or not.
为什么我的意见对你这么重要
And why does my opinion matter to you so much
以至于让你费尽心思
that you would go through all this?
你的意见对我来说不重要
Your opinion doesn't matter to me.
你的发展才重要
Your development does.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
你要我大声说出来吗
Oh, you're gonna make me say it out loud?
你让我想起了从前的我
You remind me of me.
我要怎么做才能成为现在的你
And what do I have to do to get to be like you?
你一定知道
Well, you should know.
你读了我糟糕的演讲稿
You read my damn speech.
你是说我重写了你那糟糕的演讲稿
You mean I rewrote your damn speech.
该死  我说出口了
Oh, shit, I said it.
我就宽宏大量原谅你了
I'm going to show you mercy,
鉴于你选裙子的眼光
considering your dress choice.
我的裙子怎么了
What's wrong with my dress?
你不知道有多糟糕
Oh, you don't know.
拜托  这条挺特别
Come on, this is really special.
你想知道真相吗
You wanna know the truth?
我认为你抑制了对唐娜的怒气
I think you bottled up your anger at Donna,
在路易身上发泄了出来
let it out at Louis,
然后当怒火再一次燃烧时
and then when it came back at you,
你又压了下去
you pushed it down again.
简直是胡扯
That's bullshit.
专业的医学术语称之为情感转移
The clinical term is displacement,
治疗方法就是把对唐娜的怒火发泄出来
and the cure for it is letting your anger at Donna out.
我不会那么做的
Well, I'm not gonna do that,
因为即使我会  唐娜也不在这
because even if I would, Donna's not here.
不  我没说你必须对唐娜发火
No, I didn't say you had to let it out at Donna.
你可以对我发泄
You can let it out at me.
-那太蠢了  -一点也不蠢
- That's stupid. - No, it isn't.
如果她现在就在这里
If she were here right now,
你脑海中出现的第一句话是什么
what's the first thing that comes to your mind?
唐娜  你在这做什么
Hey, Donna, what are you doing here?
如果我回答  我是为你而来的
What if I said, "I'm here for you"?
我会说  你不是应该在路易的办公室吗
I'd say, "Shouldn't you be at Louis's desk?"
我确实从他那来  这么说你感觉如何
And what if I were? How would that make you feel?
我感觉角色扮演太愚蠢了
It would make me feel like role play is stupid,
因为你不是唐娜
because you're not Donna,
我也不在乎你的学位怎么说
and I don't give a shit what your degree says.
我不想为了拿点药
I'm not gonna go through this again
就又来这一套
just to get more pills.
我可能不是唐娜
Well, I may not be Donna,
但我开始了解她的感受了
but I'm beginning to see what it's like to be her.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我在说  我是一个一直被你欺压
I'm talking about I'm a woman
以使你得到一切的女人
who you've been bullying to get what you want.
欺压  我付你钱了
Bullying? I'm paying you.
那并不代表我是为了你的需求而存在
And that doesn't mean that I exist to serve your needs.
可理应如此
Well, it goddamn should.
如果你是这么对唐娜说话的
If you spoke to Donna that way,
难怪她会离开你
no wonder she left you.
因为金钱是不能买到忠诚的
Because you don't just pay people to be loyal.
你怎么敢这么说我
How dare you?
我根本不在乎钱
I don't give a shit about the money, and I never did.
你是不在乎
No, you didn't.
钱只是你让我对你言听计从的工具
It was just a way to get me to do what you wanted.
难道当你命悬一线的时候
So when your life was on the line
我一直支持着你
and I was there for you every step of the way,
这对你来说什么都不算么
it meant nothing?
并不是一直
It wasn't every step of the way.
一旦我想要的更多你就退缩了
You bailed out the second I wanted more.
于是你就决定背叛我
That's when you decided to betray me.
放下过去  把我自己放在第一位
How the hell is moving on and putting myself first
怎么就是背叛你了
betraying you?
因为你去了路易那里
Because you went to Louis to do it,
这不是放下过去向前看
and that's not moving on.
是在我身上插了把刀再转两下
That's sticking a knife in my gut and twisting it.
是的  哈维  没错
Yeah, Harvey, it is.
当你是那个被捅的人的时候感觉如何
How does it feel to be on the receiving end for once?
哈维  你听见我说话了吗
Harvey, did you hear me?
我问  当得知你迈出了
I said, how does it feel to know that
重获控制的第一步时  你感觉如何
you've taken the first step towards regaining control?
当有人捅了你一刀
When someone twists a knife in your gut,
我只想捅回去
I feel like I want to twist one right back.
赞恩先生  你安排了这次听证会
Mr. Zane, you scheduled this hearing.
我们已经等了十分钟了
We've been waiting ten minutes.
我不打算再等了
I'm not waiting any longer.
您不需要了  法官大人
Uh, you don't have to, your honor.
我的动议到了
My motion is here.
你最好快点送上来
It better get up here fast.
你去哪儿了
Where the hell were you?
我在这里无所是事
I'm standing up here with my dick in my hand,
你还不紧不慢的
and you're out having a soda.
我有事要处理
I had something to do.
不管是什么事
Yeah, well, whatever it was,
我希望值得你为之差点输了这场官司
I hope it was worth almost losing this case over.
请求加速审判的动议
Motion to expedite trial.
我以为这是一个有关撤销案件的听证会呢
I thought this was a hearing on their motion to dismiss.
如果您加速审判的话
Well, if you expedite our trial,
就不需要撤销本案了
that takes care of their motion to dismiss.
法官大人  他们两天前才拿到这个案子
Your Honor, they just got this case two days ago.
他们想利用我们客户合同到期的时间点
They're using the timing of our client's contract expiration
敲诈我们
to try to shake us down.
我必须说  赞恩先生  我很难相信
I have to say, Mr. Zane, I find it hard to believe
两天的时间你就收集了足够的证据
that in two days you've found out enough
发现需要加速审判了
to know you need an expedited trial,
跟别提关心这些人了
let alone care about these people at all.
法官大人  四年前
Your Honor, four years ago,
一个叫做斯坦利・鲍威尔的邮差
a mail carrier named Stanley Powell
感到胸口发闷
felt tightness in his chest.
他觉得没什么大碍
He thought it was nothing,
但他的妻子坚持让他去医院看看
but his wife insisted he go to the hospital.
当他到了那儿
When he got there,
医生查不出什么问题
doctors couldn't find anything wrong,
但他们希望他能留院观察一天
but they wanted to keep him for one extra day.
但不幸的是
Now unfortunately,
凯尔顿保险公司拒绝承担这笔费用
Kelton Insurance refused to pay.
于是鲍威尔先生就回家了  爬上了床
So Mr. Powell went home, crawled into bed,
第二天  他就去世了
and one day later, he was dead.
在您面前  是一份长达五千页的
In front of you, you have a complaint
起诉书
that's over 5,000 pages long,
讲述了其他189个受害者的故事
which tells the stories of another 189 victims.
随便挑一页  告诉我页码
Pick a page at random, tell me the number,
我会一字不差的告诉您他们的客户对他们做了什么
and I will tell you exactly what their client did to them.
法官大人  您真的相信他这套么
Your Honor, are you actually buying that?
第627页  劳
Page 627, Mr.--
劳伦斯・格林
Lawrence Green.
六十三岁的一位祖父
63-year-old grandfather,
因为腰背部疼痛和严重的体重下降
admitted to St. Vincent with complaints of lower back pain
被圣文森特医院接收入院
and excessive weight loss.
他以为是因为压力过大  结果是因为淋巴瘤
He thought it was stress. Turns out it was lymphoma.
但他们发现时已经太晚了
Only they didn't find out until it was too late
因为他们的客户拒绝支付核磁共振的费用
because their client refused to pay for the MRI.
所以  如果您一定要驳回我们的动议请便
So please, rule against us if you have to,
但别说我们不在乎
but don't tell me we don't care.
加速审判动议通过
Motion for expedited trial granted.
下周一选陪审团成员
Jury selection starts Monday.
顺便说一句  这是我之前在做的事
For your information, that's what I was doing.
之所以花了这么久
And it only took as long as it did
是因为我同时在为唯一一个
because I was also doing something for the one person
有权把我当做他的助理律师
who has the right to treat me like his associate
却把我当做合伙人对待的人做事
but treats me like his partner anyway.
如果你能原谅我的话
Well, if you can forgive me,
我带我的合伙人去吃个午饭你看如何
what do you say I take my partner out to lunch?
斯佩克特先生
Mr. Specter--
格蕾琴  不管什么事  都等明天再说
Gretchen, whatever it is, it can wait till tomorrow.
恐怕这不能等
I'm afraid this can't wait.
这是你的简历
This is your resume.
我想解释一下我职业生涯中的
I wanted to explain the two-year gap
两年中断期
in my employment history.
你不需要这么做
You don't have to do that.
我的丈夫去世了
My husband passed away.
我的孩子长大了
My children were grown.
我没有了目标  感觉很孤独
I had no purpose, I felt alone,
于是我开始有恐慌症
and I started having panic attacks.
我为什么需要知道这些
And why would I need to know that?
因为我现在没有了
Because I don't have them anymore.
晚安  格蕾琴
Good night, Gretchen.
那是什么情况
What was that all about?
了解我的新秘书
Getting to know my new secretary.
你是来炫耀帮我搞定了杰克的吗
Did you come by just to brag about helping me with Jack?
看来他认输了
I take it that means he backed down.
就像罗伯特・杜兰面对苏格・雷一样
Like Roberto Duran against Sugar Ray.
完全不是对手
No match.
说正经的
Seriously...
你还好吗
you okay?
我好得很  谢谢
Yeah, I'm fine. Thanks.
想吃点什么吗
Want to get a bite or something?
当然
Sure.
我得提前告诉你  我的胃里
I got to warn you, my stomach's still full
还塞满了和罗伯特・赞恩的午餐呢
from my lunch with Robert Zane.
哎呦  你们都开始共进午餐了嘛
Oh, we're lunching now, are we?
怎么  吃醋了
Why, you jealous?
没有  只是我以为你们是在合作案子
No, I just thought you guys were working a case,
不是去公园野餐
not picnicking in a park.
我得跟你说  那可不是野餐那么愉快
Let me tell you, it was no picnic.
你有没有尝试过跟他比
You ever try to go toe-to-toe with that guy
吃海鲜自助餐
over all-you-can-eat shrimp?
不是对手啊
No match.
等我几分钟
Hey, give me a few minutes.
我要解决点事
I gotta take care of something.
你再跟杰克・索罗夫一伙儿
You ever take sides with Jack Soloff against me again,
我会灭了你
I will bury you.